Avengers: Doomsday is a science fiction, action,
adventure film directed by Joe Russo.
The Avengers, Wakandans, Fantastic Four, Thunderbolts,
and X-Men all fight against Doctor Doom.
Thor, played by Chris Hemsworth.
Sue Storm / The Invisible Woman, played by Vanessa Kirby.
Sam Wilson / Captain America, played by Anthony Mackie.
Bucky Barnes / Winter Soldier, played by Sebastian Stan.
Shuri, played by Letitia Wright.
Scott Lang / Ant-Man, played by Paul Rudd.
Avengers: Doomsday is an upcoming American superhero film based
on the Marvel Comics superhero team the Avengers.
Produced by Marvel Studios and AGBO, and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures, it is intended to be
the sequel to Avengers: Endgame (2019) and the 39th film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
Directed by Anthony and Joe Russo and written by Michael Waldron and Stephen McFeely, the film features an ensemble cast including Chris Hemsworth, Vanessa Kirby, Anthony Mackie, Sebastian Stan, Letitia Wright, Paul Rudd, Wyatt Russell, Tenoch Huerta Mejía, Ebon Moss-Bachrach, Simu
Liu, Florence Pugh, Kelsey Grammer, Lewis Pullman, Danny Ramirez, Joseph Quinn, David Harbour, Winston Duke, Hannah John-Kamen, Tom Hiddleston, Patrick Stewart, Ian McKellen, Alan Cumming, Rebecca Romijn, James Marsden, Channing Tatum, Pedro Pascal, and Robert Downey Jr.
In the film, the Avengers, Wakandans, Fantastic Four, New Avengers,
and the X-Men team up to face Doctor Doom (Downey).
Two new Avengers films, The Kang Dynasty and Secret Wars, were announced in July 2022
as the conclusion of the MCU's Phase Six and "The Multiverse Saga".
Destin Daniel Cretton was hired to direct The Kang Dynasty and Jonathan Majors
was set to reprise his MCU role as the villain Kang the Conqueror.
Jeff Loveness joined the film as writer that September.
In November 2023, Cretton departed, Waldron replaced Loveness as writer, and Marvel was considering moving away
from the Kang storyline, in part due to Majors's legal issues; Majors was fired the following month.
The return of the Russo brothers as directors and McFeely as co-writer, the casting of Downey as new
villain Doctor Doom, and the new subtitle Doomsday were all announced in July 2024.
Filming began in April 2025 at Pinewood Studios in England, with a large cast consisting mainly of actors
from previous MCU media and 20th Century Fox's X-Men film series, and wrapped in September.
Location filming took place in England and Bahrain.
Avengers: Doomsday is scheduled to be released in the United States on
December 18, 2026, as part of Phase Six of the MCU.
The sequel, Avengers: Secret Wars, is set to be released on December 17, 2027.
The film explores themes of superhero, based on comic, sequel,
superhero team, marvel cinematic universe (mcu).
The tone is thought_provoking.